[Music]
compared to sedentary individuals
Physically Active men and women may have
a approximately 30% lower risk of
premature death even just walking 15
minutes a day May reduce mortality Risk
by
15% mortality rates continue to drop
about 4% three traditional 15 minutes of
moderate exercise a day like walking
plateauing out at about 90 minutes a day
what does that translate to in terms of
time the life expectancy for those
walking just 15 minutes a day would be
about 3 years longer compared to those
who don't exercise regularly and those
meeting the recommended 30 minutes a day
live about four years longer if you jog
a few hours a week or in the top 5% % of
cardiorespiratory Fitness you may live
five or six years
longer exercising for 20 minutes may add
an hour to your life so for all those
who say they don't have time to work out
exercising gives us like a 3 to1 return
on investment give 20 minutes of your
life to get 60 Minutes of Life uh beyond
that there's a bit of diminishing
returns but exercise an hour a day and
maybe get back more time than you put in
the return for vigorous exercise may be
even greater as much as 7 to one an hour
of running could potentially extend your
life 7 hours running even 5 to 10
minutes a day at a jogging Pace less
than 6 M hour me at the same longevity
benefits of the 15 minutes of daily
walking similarly running 15 to 20
minutes a day may be equivalent to
walking an hour a day and 25 minutes of
running can match walking's maximum
mortality benefits that top off at
around 100 minutes the benefits of
running however continue to increase
until about 45 minutes a day walking is
the most commonly reported exercise and
though it is not as time effective as
running it's easier and safer to start
and sustain particularly if you like
much of the population are starting out
sedentary walking is among the safest of
physical activities averaging only about
one injury per thousand hours not using
your cell phone and walking against
traffic when on roads without sidewalks
can reduce pedestrian injuries in
contrast nearly 70% of serious Runners
become injured over a year-long period
suffering most commonly from knee
problems there does not appear to be an
increased risk of knee
osteoarthritis though in all but the
most elite long-distance Runners who who
have about three times higher odds
recreational Runners do not appear to be
at higher
risk the current official physical
activity guidelines recommend adults get
at least 150 minutes a week of moderate
aerobic exercise which comes out to be a
little more than 20 minutes a day that's
actually down from previous
recommendations from the Surgeon General
the CDC and the American College of
sports medicine for at least 30 minutes
a day this is construed as a tradeoff
between optimizing Health outcomes and
minimizing requirements for
individuals the exercise authorities
seem to have fallen into the same trap
as the nutrition authorities
recommending what they think may be
achievable rather than simply informing
you what the science says and letting
you make up your own mind they already
emphasized that any physical activity is
better than none so why not not stop
patronizing the public and just tell
everyone the
truth the optimal dose of exercise for
maximizing longevity remains uncertain
but a pulled analysis of more than a
half million men and women follow for an
average of more than a dozen years found
that mortality rates bottomed out at
about 90 minutes a day of moderate
intensity physical activity mostly
walking compared to no regular exercise
though exercising just about 30 minutes
a day gets you about 80% of the way to
the maximum exercise benefit older
adults are also encouraged to do both
muscle strengthening and flexibility
training at least twice a week along
with incorporating balance
exercises instead of exercise measured
in minutes what about measured in steps
nonagenarians those in their 90s in the
Sardinian Blue Zone average about 12,000
steps a day just living their lives
based on a representative sample of
thousands of us adults those getting
12,000 steps a day had a 65% lower risk
of dying over the subsequent decade
compared to those getting only 4,000
steps a day even just getting 8,000 to
day appeared to cut the risk of
premature death in half a study more
than 15,000 older us women found that
just 4,400 steps a day could reduce
mortality rates compared to 2700 steps a
day ra ing the question is 4,400 steps
per day the new 10,000 steps per day
where did the 10,000 steps a day
recommendation even come from
surprisingly it likely originated as the
brand name of a Japanese pedometer sold
in
1965 called meno Kai or 10,000 steps
meter in terms of walking the
recommendation for 150 minutes a week of
moderate intensity aerobic exercise
excise gets us to approximately 7,000
steps a day the maximum longevity dose
of around 90 minutes a day technically
22.5 to 40 so-called met hours a week
would give most people a total of about
13,500 steps per
[Music]
day
for